A Guide to the Lucy Herndon Crockett Papers, 1940-2015, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Lucy Herndon Crockett Papers, 1940-2015, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Crockett, Lucy Herndon, 1914-2002
Ms2011-032
2.6 Cubic Feet 3 boxes; 1 folder
The Lucy Herndon Crockett Papers consists of type and manuscript versions of some of Crockett's published and unpublished novels, her illustrations and art for her publications, and a small group of personal papers and papers about her. Materials date from about 1940 to 2015.
Adminstrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The original collections of materials for the Lucy Herndon Crockett Papers were purchased by Special Collections in two separate accruals in 2011. Additional materials were purchased by Special Collections in 2014 and 2015.
Biographical Note
Lucy Herndon Crockett (born 4 April 1914 in Honolulu, Hawaii) was a Red Cross worker in the Pacific during World War II. She travelled as a speech writer and secretary for the chairman of the American Red Cross. An author of nine books, illustrator and designer, she wrote the 1954 book The Magnificent Bastards about her experiences with the U.S. Marine Corps (the book was later made into a film) and Popcorn on the Ginza about her time in occupied Japan. Later in her life, she lived in Seven Mile Ford, Virginia.
Bibliography:
1939-Lucio and His Nuong: A Tale of the Philippine Islands 1940-Capitan: The Story of an Army Mule 1941-The Mario 1942-Uncle Bouqui of Haiti 1949-Popcorn on the Ginza: An Informal Portrait of Postwar Japan 1950-Teru: A Tale of Yokohama 1953-The Magnificent Bastards (Movie- The Proud and Profane) 1960-The Year Something Almost Happened in Pinoso 1963- Pong Choolie You Rascal!
Scope and Content Note
The Lucy Herndon Crockett Papers consists of type and manuscript versions of some of Crockett's published and unpublished novels, her illustrations and art for her publications, and a small group of personal papers and papers about her. Materials date from about 1940 to 2015.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series.
Series I: Personal Papers includes materials from 1941 to 2015. This series contains book previews, biographical information and photographs, correspondence, newspaper clippings, non-fiction writing, and land documents relating to Crockett's home at Seven Mile Ford. This series is arranged by type of material. Within each material type, folders are in chronological order.
Series II: Illustrations and Art consist of ink and pencil drawings and illustrations by Crockett, primarily for her own works. Identified illustrations include art for >, Popcorn on the Ginza: An Informal Portrait of Postwar Japan and Teru: A Tale of Yokohama. A number of the illustrations are not clearly associated with one project and could be for her works, though she was also know to illustrate for other authors. This series is arranged by size and items relating to a specific known project are house separate from unidentified art.
Series III: Manuscript and Typescript Works conatins various drafts of published and unpublished works, dating from 1940 to 1972. Drafts of published works include: Capitan, Popcorn on the Ginza: An Informal Portrait of Postwar Japan, Teru: A Tale of Yokohama, Magnificent Bastards, and Kings Without Castles. The series also has two versions of an unpublished manuscript for "The Devil Chasers" and a partial manuscript for "Bus Station Blues," dated September 1972. This series in arranged in chronological order by publication/creation date.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Women -- History; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South
Persons:
Crockett, Lucy Herndon, 1914-2002
- Series I: Personal Papers 1941-2015, n.d.
  - Book Previews (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Biographical Material, 1941-2003 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1967 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1979-2015 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1941-2005 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Personal Notes, 1938-1975 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Photographs, 1949-1988 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - The Proud and the Profane, 1956 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Religious Writings and Publications, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Seven Mile Ford Land Survey, 1959 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Seven Mile Ford Publication (Box-folder 1-11)
- Series II: Illustrations and Art
  - Illustrations, Popcorn on the Ginza, 1949 (Box-folder 1-12)
  - Illustrations (Box-folder 1-13)
  - Titles pages, Teru: A Tale of Yokohama (Folder 1)
  - Illustrations and Art (Folder 2)
- Series III: Manuscript and Typescript Works, 1940-1972
  - Captain, Part 1, 1940 (Box-folder 1-14)
  - Captain, Part 2, 1940 (Box-folder 1-15)
  - Popcorn on the Ginza: An Informal Portrait of Post-War Japan, Part 1, 1949 (Box-folder 1-16)
  - Popcorn on the Ginza: An Informal Portrait of Post-War Japan, Part 2, 1949 (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Teru: A Tale of Yokohama, Part 1, 1950 (Box-folder 1-18)
  - Teru: A Tale of Yokohama, Part 2, 1950 (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Magnificent Bastards Manuscript, Pages 1-69, 1954 (Box-folder 1-20)
  - Magnificent Bastards Manuscript, Pages 70-157, 1954 (Box-folder 1-21)
  - Magnificent Bastards Manuscript, Pages 158-223, 1954 (Box-folder 1-22)
  - Magnificent Bastards Manuscript, Pages 224-305, 1954 (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Magnificent Bastards Manuscript, Pages 306-385, 1954 (Box-folder 1-24)
  - Magnificent Bastards Manuscript, Chapter 1, 1954 (Box-folder 1-25)
  - Kings Without Castles, Part 1, 1957 (Box-folder 1-26)
  - Kings Without Castles, Part 2, 1957 (Box-folder 1-27)
  - The Devil Chasers, Volume 1 [Version 1], 1961 (Box-folder 2-1)
  - The Devil Chasers, Volume 1 [Version 2], Chapters 1-3, 1961 (Box-folder 2-2)
  - The Devil Chasers, Volume 1 [Version 3], Chapters 1-3, 1961 (Box-folder 2-3)
  - The Devil Chasers, Volume 2 [Version 1], Chapters 1-3, 1961 (Box-folder 2-4)
  - The Devil Chasers, Volume 2 [Version 2], Chapters 2-3, 1961 (Box-folder 2-5)
  - The Devil Chasers, Volume 2 [Version 3], Chapters 1-3, 1961 (Box-folder 2-6)
  - The Devil Chasers, Volume 3 [Various Volumes], Chapter 1, 1961 (Box-folder 2-7)
  - The Devil Chasers, Volume 4, Chapter 1, 1961 (Box-folder 2-8)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 1, 1961 (Box-folder 2-9)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 2, 1961 (Box-folder 2-10)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 3, 1961 (Box-folder 2-11)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 4, 1961 (Box-folder 2-12)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 5, 1961 (Box-folder 2-13)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 6, 1961 (Box-folder 2-14)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 7, 1961 (Box-folder 2-15)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 8, 1961 (Box-folder 2-16)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 9, 1961 (Box-folder 2-17)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 10, 1961 (Box-folder 2-18)
  - The Devil Chasers, Chapter 11, 1961 (Box-folder 2-19)
  - The Devil Chasers, Epilogue, 1961 (Box-folder 2-20)
  - The Devil Chasers, Mixed Manuscripts, 1961 (Box-folder 2-21)
  - The Devil Chasers, Original Box Labels (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Bus Station Blues, 1972 (Box-folder 3-1)